Whether it’s studying for exams, working on a project or struggling with a dissertation, we’ve all been under immense stress at some point.
不管是备考、做项目还是绞尽脑汁写论文，我们每个人都有过承受巨大压力的时刻。
When it gets a bit overwhelming, we can reach a level of exhaustion that is unprecedented – the dreaded burnout.
当压力大到让人难以承受时，我们会陷入一种前所未有的疲惫状态——也就是令人闻之色变的职业倦怠。
However, that feeling of exhaustion is not just physical; it can be mental as well.
但这种疲惫感不只是身体上的，也可能是精神层面的。
According to ‘Psychology Today’, burnout isn’t just caused by working long hours; it is more about prolonged or repeated exposure to a stressful situation.
据《今日心理学》杂志称，职业倦怠的成因不只是长时间工作，更多是源于长期或反复置身于充满压力的环境中。
The result can be feelings of cynicism, depression and lethargy.
其后果可能是产生愤世嫉俗、抑郁消沉和无精打采的情绪。
A feeling of loss of control in a work scenario can create a conflict with the sense of self – which can lead to burnout.
在工作场景中失去掌控感，会让人的自我认知产生矛盾，进而引发职业倦怠。
Suffering from burnout can stifle our creativity and productivity.
陷入职业倦怠的状态会扼杀我们的创造力和工作效率。
Ironically, this means that striving to be more efficient can result in a reduction in our productivity.
颇具讽刺意味的是，这意味着越是拼命追求高效，反而越会导致效率下降。
But what can we do to avoid the evils of burnout?
那么，我们该如何避免职业倦怠的危害呢？
Well, there are some tips that may help you.
其实有一些小技巧可以帮到你。
Psychologist Albert Bandura’s idea of self-efficacy – which is the theory that you should believe in your ability to complete a task at hand - may assist you.
心理学家阿尔伯特·班杜拉提出的自我效能感理论或许能帮到你，该理论的核心是，你要相信自己有能力完成手头的任务。
A feeling that the task is achievable and that you are capable of succeeding means that a difficult task might be less gruelling.
当你觉得任务是可以完成的，并且自己有能力成功时，再棘手的任务也会变得没那么费力。
Finding ways to express your creative side may help.
找到释放创造力的途径也会有所帮助。
Not everyone has creative aspects to their jobs, and, therefore, they need to find other outlets.
并非所有人的工作都带有创造性，因此他们需要寻找其他的宣泄渠道。
They could paint, write or take part in local theatre.
比如画画、写作，或是参与当地的戏剧表演。
All of this may help to detach them from the overwhelming stress that may exist in their working life.
这些活动都能帮助人们暂时摆脱工作中难以承受的压力。
Looking after yourself and your surroundings can also be beneficial.
照顾好自己和身处的环境同样有益。
The consequence is that you are surrounded by a cleaner and more positive environment.
这样做的结果是，你会被一个更整洁、更积极的环境所包围。
This, in turn, leads to another tip, which is to have healthy and positive thoughts.
这一点又引出了另一个技巧，那就是保持健康积极的心态。
Being negative can be incredibly draining.
消极的心态会让人身心俱疲。
Having a positive mental attitude towards everything you do means that you may feel more capable as well.
无论做什么事都抱着积极的心态，也会让你觉得自己更有能力应对挑战。
Burnout is a common condition associated with the pressures of the modern world.
职业倦怠是一种与现代社会压力相伴而生的普遍状态。
It’s not just a physical condition; it has psychological effects that can impact heavily on your work and life in general.
它不只是一种身体上的不适，其带来的心理影响还会严重干扰我们的工作和日常生活。
Taking steps to avoid burning out can benefit not just us, but our bosses and families.
采取措施预防职业倦怠，不仅对我们自己有益，也能惠及我们的上司和家人。